Is very difficult to speak, even for Me
即使對我來說，也很難說些甚麼..
to see so many Sahaja yogis
看到這麼多霎哈嘉瑜伽士
sitting here with such shining faces
面容如此光彩照人地坐在這裡——
from all over the world,
來自世界各地
as if My vision has taken its form today.
彷彿我的願景今日已成形。
I see in you the saviors of tomorrow
我在你們身上看見明日的救世主
who are going to save this world
將要拯救這個世界
from all the Kali Yuga calamities
使其免於環繞著我們的種種災難
that are surrounding us.
的爭鬥世
Is coming from all sides,
的種種災難。
while you people have really taken your second birth
而你們這些人確實已從這爭鬥世的池塘中
from this pond of Kali Yuga
獲得了第二次新生
and have really become beautiful lotuses of different colors,
並已真正成為不同顏色的美麗蓮花，
hues, fragrance and beauty.
色澤、芬芳與美麗。
Instead of you celebrating My birthday,
與其由你來慶祝我的生日，
is better I celebrate your birthdays.
不如讓我來慶祝你們的生日。[掌聲]
As I told you the other day that
正如我前幾天告訴你的那樣
it is you who are such great seekers, seekers of truth, of love,
正是你們這些如此偉大的求道者，追尋真理、追尋愛的人，
that it could work out,
才能讓事情成功，
otherwise it would have been impossible.
否則這將是不可能的。
To even transform one person is very difficult,
要改變一個人是非常困難的，
but you were so sensitive
但你卻如此敏銳
and so deep that this subtle knowledge,
且如此深刻，以至於這種精微的知識，
I don't know how it penetrated your being.
我不知道它是如何滲透到你的存在中。
It's unbelievable.
這簡直令人難以置信。
I can't believe Myself
我連自己都無法相信
what great people have taken birth in this Kali Yuga.
在這個爭鬥世，竟有如此偉大的人類誕生。
No one can believe that there are so many
沒有人能相信竟然有這麼多
saints are sitting before Me, so many Walis;
聖人們正坐在我面前，如此多的道家；
so many Nalis are sitting before Me.
如此多的聖賢正坐在我面前。
In the history of spirituality it has never happened.
在靈性歷史上，這從未發生過。
Even in the heavens there are few devatas
即使在天堂中，也只有少數的天神──
and devas, not so many.
沒有那麼多──而且
One better than the other
一個比一個更勝一籌
such beautiful heart,
如此美麗的心靈，
such brilliant brains
如此卓越的智慧
and such active attention, is really
而這般積極的關注，確實
I thank you all that this seventieth birthday I could see
我感謝大家，讓我在七十歲生日時能見到
so many people, which I never expected.
這麼多人，這是我從未預料到的。
You know, Sahaja Yoga was started with one person
霎哈嘉瑜珈最初只有一個人，
and then those who came also,
接著，那些後來加入的人，
out of them, some were power-oriented, money-oriented,
其中有些人追求權力，有些人追求金錢，
all kinds of people created problems for us.
各式各樣的人給我們製造了麻煩。
One after another, so many problems came
一個接一個，問題接踵而至。
and also there were many who were
而且也有許多人是
of a very low-level seekers.
層次非常低的求道者。
But I find today they have all come up beautifully.
但我發現如今他們都已經成長得非常出色。
I cannot distinguish one from another,
我已經無法區分他們之間的差異。
the way it has happened.
事情就是這樣發生的。
And the commitment you have to Sahaja Yoga
而你對霎哈嘉瑜伽的奉獻
is the greatest blessings for this world.
是對這個世界最大的祝福。
I could not do it alone. You know that.
我無法獨自完成。你知道的。
If I could do it, I would not have needed you.
如果我能做到，就不需要你們了。
You are the channels
你們是管道
and you have to work it out further and further.
你們必須繼續努力，不斷完善它。
It is really remarkable the way
這方式確實非凡。
Delhi people have organized everything.
德里的人們已經把一切都安排妥當了[掌聲]。
First of all, everybody was very much
首先，每個人都非常
keyed onto the seventieth birthday.
專注於七十歲生日這件事。
I don't know what was the reason, but whatever it is,
我不知道原因是什麼，但無論如何，
and then Delhi people said,
然後德里瑜珈士說，
"This time we are going to celebrate,
「這次我們要在德里慶祝，
Mother, Your birthday in Delhi."
母親，您的生日。」
I said, "Everybody's ... on it, so be careful,
我說：「大家都關注，所以要小心，」
it's not going to be easy. It's a big headache.
這不會是件容易的事。會很麻煩。
So many will be coming down."
因為會有很多人來。
But they didn't expect so much, I'm sure
但我敢肯定，他們沒料到會有這麼多
... people are coming. Hundred are coming from there,
……人們正不斷湧來。從那邊就有上百人要過來，
hundred from there. I said, "Are you worried?"
一百個人從那裡來，我說：「你們擔心嗎？」
They said, "No we are very happy about it."
他們說：「不，我們對此感到非常高興。」
I saw their enthusiasm, their organization,
我看到了他們的熱情、他們的組織能力，
the way they have done it.
以及他們完成這件事的方式。
The best part of it,
最棒的部分是，
Delhi, which is a place where all kinds of politicians live,
德里，一個各類政治人物聚集的地方，
have groups and politics and all that,
充滿了派系和政治鬥爭等等，
but in Sahaja Yoga in Delhi there is no politics.
但在德里的霎哈嘉瑜伽中，完全沒有政治[掌聲]。
There is no quarrelling.
沒有爭吵，
There is no pulling each other's legs.
沒有互相嘲諷。
Is very remarkable thing
是非常了不起的事情
it to happen in a place like Delhi,
竟然發生在德里這樣的地方。
where every day what you hear
在這裡，每一天你所聽聞的
that even in our parliament they are beating each other.
即便在我們的議會中，他們也在互相毆打。
Perhaps, in this hell only,
或許，唯有在這或許正是在這人間煉獄之中，
this goodness was to be born and
這份良善才得以誕生。
to be manifested by Sahaja yogis.
由霎哈嘉瑜伽士所展現。
The knowledge of Sahaja Yoga,
霎哈嘉瑜伽的知識，
as you know, is extremely, extremely subtle
如你所知，是極其、極其精微的
and it's not easy
並且不容易掌握。
to penetrate into the so-called
深入所謂的
people who call themselves intellectuals
自稱知識分子的人
or who are absolutely bowed down to their conditionings.
或完全屈服於自身制約的人。
So, on one side, we have the masses who are ignorant,
因此，一方面，我們有無知的大眾，
another side the classes who live in the frame
另一邊是那些活在框架中的階級
that they have made out of their brains.
那是他們用頭腦構築出來的。
Both ways, I think, they are extremely gross.
在我看來，這兩種方式都極其粗鄙。
But the way they have absorbed
但他們吸收的方式
this subtle nectar of Divinity is something unbelievable.
這神聖的精微甘露令人難以置信。
Nobody can comprehend even
甚至無人能夠理解
that there were so many born after My birth,
在我誕生之後，竟有如此多的人出生於世，
on this Earth,
在這片大地上。
or some maybe before also, very few.
或許有些人更早，但為數不多。
Just after My birth they were born here
就在我出生後，他們也在此誕生
in this world, to get to Sahaja Yoga.
於這個世界，為了進入霎哈嘉瑜伽。
But when I saw the world I was shocked,
但當我來到這個世界時，我感到震驚，
more shocked than Kabira, himself.
比卡比爾本人還要震驚。
I said, "How will I talk to anyone about it?"
我說：「我該如何向任何人談論這件事？」
My family members,
我的家人們，
I didn't know how will I open the subject to them.
我不知道該如何向他們提起這個話題。
Was impossible, so much was darkness of ignorance.
這是不可能的，因為無知的黑暗如此深重。
How will they believe that there is really Divinity,
他們如何能相信真的有神性存在，
there is totality waiting for them?
有圓滿的境界在等待著他們？
They all believed into some sort of a religion,
他們都信奉
which had no connection with reality.
某種與現實毫無關聯的宗教，
And it was impossible even to envisage
我完全無法想像
the method by which I could talk to them.
該如何與他們溝通。
I remember the first incident
我記得第一起事件
when we went to Nargol, where I had opened the Sahasrara.
當我們前往納爾戈爾，那是我開啟頂輪的地方。
The first person who got realization was a Gujarati and a jeweler.
第一位獲得自覺的是一位古吉拉特人，也是一位珠寶商。
Immediately, all the other,
緊接著，所有其他人，
there were hardly about thirty-five people
當時大約只有三十五個人
they started saying that
他們開始這麼說
"Of course, he's a rich man, he's a jeweler,
"當然，他是個有錢人，他是珠寶商，
so Mother has given him realization."
所以母親已經讓他自覺。"
I think that's the first time and last time I really got angry.
我想那是我第一次也是最後一次真正生氣。
I started shouting at them,
我開始對他們大喊大叫，
"You are good for nothing, useless people,
「你們一無是處，沒用的人，
you can never take to Divinity,"
你們永遠無法接近神性，」
and I had really thought that "Stop it now."
而我當時真的以為「現在就停下來。」
One has to take another life,
必須在另一個世代再來降世，
another time where people will understand what is Sahaja Yoga.
在另一個時代，人們將會理解什麼是霎哈嘉瑜伽。
But after that, suddenly,
但之後，就在我生氣之後，突然間，
people started feeling the cool breeze in their hands,
人們開始感受到手中的涼風。
immediately, after My shouting. Imagine.
就在我呼喊之後。想像一下。
And they said, "Mother, You know, it's working.
他們說：「母親，您知道，這正在起作用。
It's working in us. It's working out of us."
它正在我們裡面起作用。它正在從我們身上顯現出來。」
Thus, we got twelve people
就這樣，我們得到了十二個人。
and one lady whom I had given before also,
而我之前也曾給予一位女士，
she was the fourteenth.
她是第十四位。
Thus, first we had only these fourteen Sahaja yogis,
因此，最初我們只有這十四位霎哈嘉瑜伽士，
for whom it was something out of the blue.
對他們來說，這完全是出乎意料的事。
They were all flabbergasted.
他們全都驚呆了。
They didn't know what it was.
他們不知道那是什麼。
And then, surprisingly, in one of our programs,
然後，令人驚訝的是，在我們的一個活動，
a lady who was possessed by some Brahmin came
一位被某位婆羅門附身的女士出現了
and started saying, "Jagadamba, Jagadamba."
並開始說道：「宇宙之母杰格丹巴，杰格丹巴。」
They couldn't understand. I never told them what I was, never.
他們無法理解。我從未告訴過他們我是什麼，從來沒有。
I've never told otherwise also.
我也從未以其他方式說過。
So then, she recited a poem
於是，她朗誦了一首詩。
from Saundarya Lahari in Sanskrit language
出自梵文經典《妙音天女頌》
and she was just a maidservant.
而她不過是個女僕。
And in a man's voice.
而且用的是男人的聲音。
So everybody was shocked
所以每個人都震驚不已
that the bhoots should say all these things.
那些亡靈竟然會說出所有這些事情。
And then she went away.
然後她就離開了。
After that, these people started probing into it.
之後，這些人開始探究這件事。
And they wanted to have My Puja, first time,
他們想在我的家中進行我的第一次崇拜法會。
in My house itself.
在我家本身。
Still people were not very sure they were doing the right thing.
儘管如此，人們仍然不太確定他們做的是否正確。
Even the Brahmins they called, they said,
即使是他們請來的婆羅門也說，
"This Saptasadi is a very difficult Puja
「這七能量崇拜法會非常難，」
and something will happen to us."
我們可能會出什麼事。」
But after the Puja they said,
但在普迦儀式後他們說，
"Nothing happened, we are so much better."
「什麼事也沒發生，我們感覺好多了。」
They all felt the cool breeze
他們都感受到了那股涼風
and the entire atmosphere changed.
整個氛圍都改變了。
They started understanding that
他們開始理解到
Sahaja Yoga is the Yuga Dharma, is the one
霎哈嘉瑜伽是這個時代的正法，是這個
of this yuga, this Kali Yuga,
爭鬥世之法。
so the Sahaj Dharma became the dharma of this yuga.
因此，霎哈嘉法門成為了這個時代的法(Dharma)。
This yuga is very difficult, no doubt.
毫無疑問，這個時代非常艱難。
But in difficulties only we become intense seekers
但正是在困境中，我們才成為熱切的求道者
and that's what happened with all of you,
而這也正是你們所有人所經歷的。
that you found out that everywhere
你發現到處都是
people were following whatever they're following,
無論人們追求什麼，
they were not reaching any point.
都一事無成。
Like a cocoon,
就像一個繭一樣，
they're hitting their head here and there.
徒勞無功。
They got their realizations
他們得到了他們的自覺
so quickly and when they told Me
如此迅速，當他們告訴我
how they were seeking, what was happening to them,
他們是如何尋求的，以及他們身上發生了什麼事
I was amazed.
我感到驚嘆不已。
How this seeking was working within them
這種尋求如何在他們內心運作
and pushed them towards Sahaja Yoga.
並推動他們走向霎哈嘉瑜伽。
Also, in the meanwhile, I must say,
同時，我必須說，
so many got lost into the clutches of false gurus.
許多人迷失在假導師的掌控之中。
Despite that, today we have so many Sahaja yogis.
儘管如此，今日我們仍有許多霎哈嘉瑜伽士。
You are just representing your country,
你們僅代表著自己的國家，
but there are many more in your countries.
但在你們的國家裡還有更多人。
Even in India we have many more.
即使在印度，我們也有更多。
You are just here, come to represent them.
你就在這裡，來代表他們。
So, multiple of this number,
所以，這個數字的倍數，
I do not know how many would be there.
我不知道會有多少。
So many asked "Me how many Sahaja yogis there are". I said,
許多人問我：「有多少霎哈嘉瑜伽士？」我說，
"I don't know."
「我不知道。」
Say, "You don't know?"
他們說：「你不知道？」
I said, "No. We have never kept any record."
我說：「是的，我們從未保留任何記錄。」
So they can't understand. I said,
所以他們無法理解。我說，
"We have no office, no record. I have no secretary.
「我們沒有辦公室，沒有紀錄。我沒有秘書。
I don't know how to type.
我不會打字。
I don't know how to write even My check."
我甚至不知道怎麼寫我的支票。」
They can't understand
他們無法理解
person like Me existing in these modern times.
像我這樣的人存在於這個現代社會。
But everything gets done, somehow.
但不知何故，一切都能完成。
Despite all My modern ignorance,
儘管我對現代事物一無所知，
everything gets absolutely
一切都處理得恰到好處
done in the most perfect manner
以最完美的方式完成
like a remote control.
就像遙控器一樣。
Now this whole thing,
現在這整件事，
I never said a word about it, I must tell you, nothing.
我從未對此說過一個字，必須告訴你，什麼都沒說。
Never I gave any idea as to how it should be.
我從未給出任何關於它應該如何進行的想法。
I didn't even tell them how many we are expecting.
我甚至沒有告訴他們我們預計會有多少人。
But see how spontaneously everything has worked out
但看看一切是如何自然而然地運作起來的
because you all have commitment
因為你們都有奉獻精神，
and that commitment gives you
而正是這種奉獻精神賦予了你們
all these organizing capacities.
所有這些組織能力
So many things you have seen get organized
你們所看到的許多事情得以順利進行，
because also this Paramchaitanya
也是因為至高生命能量流（Paramchaitanya）
has come into Krita Yuga
已經降臨到銅器時代( Krita Yuga)
where it is working it out. It's acting.
它正在那裡運作，它很活躍。
And this activity, also, is absolutely supportive to you.
而這種活躍，也絕對是支持你的。
For example, the police people told us
舉例來說，警方人員告訴我們
that there are Muslims living here
這裡有回教徒居住
and you might have some danger from them.
而你們可能會因此面臨一些危險。
They might do some harm to you.
他們可能會對你們造成一些傷害。
I said, "Which Muslims are they?"
我說：「他們是哪裡的回教徒？」
So they said, "Nizamuddin Aulia's people are here."
於是他們說：「尼扎穆丁·奧利亞的人就在這裡。」
I said, "They'll never harm us."
我說：「他們絕不會傷害我們。」
I said, "Why? Because he was a Sufi
我說：「為什麼？因為他是一位蘇菲派聖人。」
and he was a great realized soul
而他是一位偉大的自覺靈，
and the people who are along there, must be, most of them are,
而那裡的人們，必定是，他們大多數都是，
at least, believers of Sufism.
至少，是蘇菲主義的信徒。
How can they harm us?"
他們怎麼可能傷害我們呢？
So I said, "Tomorrow, early in the morning,
於是我說：「明天一大早，
you go and put a chador, as they call it, all of you,"
你們都去鋪上他們所謂的‘遮頭巾’」
and they were so impressed
他們對此印象深刻
that you saw in the evening they came here all the way,
以至於你看到他們在晚上特地來到這裡
morning time, and they were so respectful.
早晨時分，他們是如此恭敬。
Then they called Me, they gave Me another chador,
接著他們呼喚我，又給了我一件遮頭巾，
this, that and they said that we are Yours and this and that,
這個、那個，還說我們是屬於您的，如此這般，
all kinds of things.
各式各樣的事情。
And his disciple was Amir Khusrau,
而他的弟子是阿米爾·胡斯勞，
was another very, very great Sufi gentleman
是另一位非常、非常偉大的蘇菲派紳士
and I always have admired his poetry
我一直很欣賞他的詩歌
and also the way Nizamuddin led his life of dignity
以及尼扎穆丁過著尊嚴生活的方式
and divinity.
與神性。
All these Muslims who were there put hands towards Me like this
所有在場的回教徒都像這樣將手伸向我
and they said, "We are feeling the cool breeze,"
他們說：「我們感受到涼爽的微風，」
I said, "This is Ruh."
我說：這就是靈（Ruh）。」「
"Ah, this is Ruh."
「啊，這就是靈（Ruh）！」
Once these people start getting Ruh,
一旦這些人開始感受到靈（Ruh），
they will all become Sahaja yogis very soon
他們很快就會成為霎哈嘉瑜伽士
and you may have to have ...
而你可能需要……（掌聲）
There are so many Sufis all over the world
世界各地有如此多的蘇菲派信徒
and we are going to take their addresses
我們要收集他們的地址，
and we are going to meet them;
然後去拜訪他們。
then you might have to have another big pendal,
屆時你可能需要另一個大型帳篷，
double pendal I think, maybe triple.
我覺得可能得雙層的，也可能是三層的（掌聲）。
If Delhi people are not quite frightened about the sizes,
你們德里人似乎不太在意大規模。
I think again we'll have to have it in Delhi only.
我想我們可能還得在德里再辦一個。
Also contemporarily,
同時，在當代，
Delhi is in a state of turmoil
德里正處於動盪之中
and we should be here to pacify it, to quieten it,
我們的到來應該能平息事態，撫慰人心，
to give wisdom to those people
並給予那些
who are supposed to be at the helm of affairs.
理應執掌事務的人們智慧。
It will work. Definitely, it will work.
它會成功的。毫無疑問，它一定會成功。
With all these Sahaja yogis
有這麼多霎哈嘉瑜伽士
emitting such beautiful, vibrations.
散發出如此美好的生命能量。
See, on top of your head
看，就在你的頭頂上
this cloth is moving up and down all the time,
這塊布一直在上下移動，
though there is no breeze outside,
雖然外面沒有微風，
the leaves are just steady,
樹葉靜止不動，
but from your head, you see, you are moving all this.
但從你的頭部來看，你看，這一切都在動。
So I'm sure these vibrations
所以我確信這些生命能量
will cool down and will bring peace
將會平息騷動，並為我們的政治人物
to our politicians and to the people
以及那些執掌事務的人們
who are at the helm of affairs.
帶來和平。
At this juncture, when in the whole world
值此之際，當全世界
there are so many things going on
有如此多事情正在發生
of uncertainties,
充滿不確定性，
say in Russia, there are uncertainties,
例如在俄羅斯，局勢動盪，
Bosnia there is uncertainties,
波士尼亞局勢動盪，
in England there's recession,
英國陷入經濟衰退，
America there is recession,
美國陷入經濟衰退，
Spain there is recession,
西班牙陷入經濟衰退，
everybody is suffering from the pangs
每個人都正經歷著某種極端行為所帶來的痛苦
of some sort of a extreme behavior they went into.
他們陷入了這種極端行為之中。
So, I'm sure this polarity
因此，我確信他們現在所看到的這種極端對立
that they see now will correct
將會修正
their behavior towards materialism
他們對物質主義的態度
and I'm sure that a balance will be struck.
我相信最終會達到平衡點。
With your good wishes, with your prayers,
有你們的美好祝願，有你們的祈禱，
this world will be so beautiful,
這個世界將會如此美好。
so enchanting that in the history,
如此迷人，以至於在歷史中，
people will describe
人們將會描述
that the world itself became a lotus
人們會將此世本身描述成一朵蓮花，
full of fragrance of Divinity.
充滿神聖的芬芳。
You are the petals,
你是那花瓣，
you are the corona,
你是那花冠，
you are the color,
你是那色彩，
you are the beauty,
你是那美麗，
you are the pollen
你就是那花粉
of that beautiful lotus
來自那朵美麗的蓮花
which is My vision of this world.
那是我對這個世界的視野。
I hope today
願今日
you all will decide to work for Sahaja Yoga,
你們都將決定為霎哈嘉瑜伽工作，
to spread Sahaja Yoga
傳播霎哈嘉瑜伽
and work for yourself also.
同時也為自己工作。
The only danger is
唯一的危險是
that one should not allow ego to sit on your heads.
不應讓自我騎在你的頭上。
That's the only horse.
那是唯一的絆腳石。
If you could ride yourself and don't allow the horse to ride you,
如果你能駕馭自己，而不是被它駕馭，
you'll progress very fast,
你將會進步得非常快。
beautifully.
步伐輕盈。
Thus, I'm sure Sahaja Yoga will spread.
因此，我確信霎哈嘉瑜伽將會傳播開來。
Every birthday we have to take a vow.
每個生日我們都必須立下誓願。
I don't know what vow I should take.
我不知道我應該立下什麼誓願。
People have told Me that I should not work so hard,
人們曾告訴我，我不該如此拼命工作，
I'm working very hard,
我確實非常努力，
but I have taken a vow that I'll work double hard.
但我已立下誓言，要加倍努力。
In the same way, you also,
同樣地，你們也該如此。
all of you, have to take a vow today
你們所有人，今天都必須立下誓言
that we'll go all out in the commitment
我們將全力以赴地投入
of working of Sahaja Yoga.
霎哈嘉瑜伽的工作。
We'll think about it.
我們會好好思考這件事。
There are scientists who should produce books,
有科學家應該出書，
there are doctors who should produce books,
有醫生應該出書，
writings,
著作，
go round,
流傳，
talk to their colleagues,
與同事交談，
organize meetings,
組織會議，
seminars with your colleagues.
與同事舉辦研討會。
There are architects
有建築師
and other professionals
以及其他專業人士
who could call their colleagues and give them realization.
能夠致電他們的同事並幫助他們自覺。。
Even the people who are dealing with finances
即使是處理財務的人們
should take to Sahaja Yoga.
也應該接觸霎哈嘉瑜伽。
Is very important because
這非常重要，因為
financial problems can only be
財務問題只能
solved by the Divine Power.
透過神聖力量來解決。
Nobody else can solve it.
沒有其他人能夠解決它。
So everyone in this world,
所以這個世界上的每一個人，
whether it is law or any other field,
無論是法律還是任何其他領域，
all of you should take to Sahaja Yoga
你們都應該接受霎哈嘉瑜伽
and also to creative work.
並且投入創造性的工作。
Then also, you have to take Sahaja Yoga
接著，你也必須將霎哈嘉瑜伽
to your surroundings,
帶到你的周遭環境中，
to villages, to cities,
帶到鄉村，帶到城市，
wherever it is possible,
任何可能的地方
wherever you can organize,
無論你在何處組織活動，
you have to spread Sahaja Yoga everywhere.
你都必須將霎哈嘉瑜伽傳播到每個角落。
As far as curing is concerned,
至於治療疾病方面，
I would advise, you don't have to touch anyone.
我建議你無需觸碰任何人。
Please use only My photograph.
請僅使用我的照片。
That's how you'll get more Sahaja yogis
這樣你就能吸引更多霎哈嘉瑜伽士
and less sick people.
而不是病人。
Also, people will be cured
此外，人們也將獲得療癒。
and all of them will become Sahaja yogis.
而他們都將成為霎哈嘉瑜伽士。
We have also agricultural field
我們也擁有農田
on which we have done something,
我們已在其上進行了一些工作，
but much can be done about agriculture.
但在農業方面仍有許多可為之處。
One should see the government and tell them
你們應該去見政府並告訴他們
what agriculture can do.
農業能做什麼。
You can form a committee and go and see them
你們可以組成一個委員會去見他們
and talk to them that
並與他們談談
how agriculture can be helped by Sahaja Yoga.
農業如何能透過霎哈嘉瑜伽獲得幫助。
We have to help our children.
我們必須幫助我們的孩子。
We have to look after them
我們必須照顧他們
because you know what sort of future is surrounding them,
因為你們知道什麼樣的未來正圍繞著他們。
what sort of atmosphere is crawling,
什麼樣的氛圍正在蔓延，
even in India.
即使在印度也是如此。
So we have to see that our children
因此我們必須確保我們的孩子
properly grow in Sahaj culture.
能在霎哈嘉文化中健康成長。
Is very important
這非常重要
because they are tomorrow's Sahaja yogis.
因為他們是明日的霎哈嘉瑜伽士
So many of them are born realized,
他們之中有許多人生來就已自覺
so we have to discipline them properly
所以我們必須妥善地引導他們
and we have to make them aala, "aala darza"
而我們必須讓他們成為「真主至尊（Allah Dairha/Dirtha？」的
Sahaja yogi, as described in the qawali.
霎哈嘉瑜珈士，正如卡瓦利歌中所描述的那樣。
It is also our family life which is very important.
同樣，我們的家庭生活也非常重要。
Is shocking that
令人震驚的是
family life is nowadays becoming
現今的家庭生活正逐漸變得
a kind of a stupid thing.
有點愚蠢。
No one understands the importance of it.
沒有人理解它的重要性。
In Sahaja Yoga we have to understand.
在霎哈嘉瑜伽中，我們必須理解。
Small quarrels, fights, should be given up.
小爭執、爭吵，應當放下。
Harshness must be given up, cruelty must be given up
嚴厲必須捨棄，殘酷必須捨棄
and there should be a proper rapport
並且應當有適當的融洽關係
between husband and wife to begin with,
從一開始，夫妻之間就應該如此。
so that there is a companionship
這樣就有了陪伴
and the children also see that companionship
孩子們也看到了那份陪伴
and enjoy it.
並樂在其中。
In our dress, in our life,
在我們的衣著中，在我們的生活裡，
we have to be dignified and decent, respecting our body.
我們必須保持莊重與得體，尊重自己的身體。
Is very important.
這是非常重要的。
We should wear whatever suits us
我們應該穿著適合自己的服裝
in whatever country we are.
無論身處哪個國家。
I mean, imagine in summer climate
我的意思是，想像一下在夏季的氣候裡
if somebody wants to wear a three-piece suit,
如果有人想穿三件式西裝，
what will happen to him?
他會發生什麼事？
Whatever suits us,
我們適合什麼就穿什麼
whatever fits our culture,
符合我們文化的服飾，
one should try to wear decent dresses,
人們應嘗試穿著得體的服裝，
traditional dresses.
傳統服飾。
Specially for women, it is very important
特別是對女性而言，這非常重要
to wear dresses that will make them look more dignified.
穿上能讓她們看起來更端莊的洋裝。
Also, another point I would like to say,
此外，我還想說另一點，
that ladies, specially, must take to reading,
特別是女士們，必須養成閱讀的習慣，
at least newspapers.
至少要看報紙。
If your attention is on the problems
如果你的注意力集中在這個世界的問題上
that are in this world, it's very effective
那會非常有效
because you know your attention is active, it works.
因為你知道你的注意力是活躍的，它會發揮作用。
So use your attention.
所以，善用你的注意力。
You see the newspapers,
你看那些報紙，
you watch -- I know it's horrifying sometimes
你觀看——我知道有時新聞真的很可怕
you can give a bandhan,
你可以給予班丹（祝福），
but you must see what's happening where,
但你必須看清楚哪裡發生了什麼事
is very important.
是非常重要的。
Also men should not just read something sensational,
此外，男性不應只閱讀聳人聽聞的內容，
but read something that's happening
而應閱讀正在發生的事情，
and also think, what are the solutions.
並思考解決方案是什麼。
How can you people, as Sahaja yogis, help it,
你們這些霎哈嘉瑜伽士，要如何協助解決，
in a collective way or in an individual way.
無論是集體方式還是個人方式。
We have to solve many problems of this modern world.
我們必須解決這個現代世界的許多問題。
Also one has to read good books,
此外，每個人都應該閱讀好書，
good films one has to see,
值得一看的好電影，
and have your reflection on them.
並對它們進行反思。
Keep your mind alert.
保持頭腦清醒。
There are many beautiful poems I've read recently
我最近讀了許多優美的詩篇
coming out of
出乎意料
some people where I never expected they will write poems,
有些人我從未預料到他們會寫詩，
beautiful, very high class.
優美，極具水準。
So this poetry also, we are going to collect.
因此這些詩作，我們也將收錄。
We are going to collect all the miraculous photographs
我們將蒐集所有奇蹟的照片
from everywhere.
來自四面八方。
They are trying to systematize now.
他們現在正試圖系統化。
And now, in this system,
而現在，在這個系統中，
if you can all help spontaneously,
如果你們都能自發地協助，
it will be a great achievement
那將是一項重大的成就
because, so far, we have not been able to collect
因為，到目前為止，我們一直無法收集
all these datas and keep them with us.
所有這些數據並將它們保存下來。
Now the best is that you all must meditate.
現在最重要的是你們都必須冥想。
All have to meditate.
每個人都必須冥想。
Only in meditation you are in present
只有在冥想中，你才能活在當下
and you grow in your spirituality.
並在靈性上成長。
I've said it many a times, but people just don't do it.
我已經說過很多次了，但人們就是不去做。
About ten minutes, if you can meditate
大約十分鐘，如果你能在睡前
before sleeping, it's of a very great help to you,
冥想，這對你會有非常大的幫助，
no doubt.
毫無疑問。
We really grow very fast.
你進步的速度會非常快。
Immediately I know this man is meditating,
我立刻就知道這個人有否冥想，
the way he has changed.
因為他的改變很明顯。
And then, once you get used to it,
然後，一旦你習慣了，
you'll never give it up.
你永遠不會放棄。
Is very simple meditation.
是非常簡單的冥想。
You have foot soaking or something like that
像是泡腳。
and in the morning you should beat your ego,
而在早晨你應該鞋打自我。
that's all.
就這樣。
Is not that you have to do
並不是說你必須做
one lakh jappas or something.
十萬個合十禮（苦行）之類的。
Nothing of the kind.
完全不是那麼回事。
Is very simple.
非常簡單。
But this, you have to do for yourself,
但這點，你必須為自己去做，
to respect your Self-realization and your growth in divinity.
以尊重你的自覺現與你在神性中的成長。
We have lots of advantages over others.
我們比他人擁有許多優勢。
But one thing I have to tell you,
但有件事我必須告訴你，
those people who are not prone to seeking,
那些不願意尋求真理的人，
please don't talk to them about Sahaja Yoga.
請不要和他們談論霎哈嘉瑜伽。
Don't waste your energy on such people,
別在這樣的人身上浪費你的精力。
discussing and arguing,
討論與爭辯，
because it cannot be discussed much.
因為這沒什麼好討論的。
You just forget them and leave them alone.
你只需忘記它們，別去管它們。
I'll look after them.
我會照顧他們的。
You just take to simple people, good people,
你只需接觸那些單純、善良的人，
who are seeking the truth.
那些正在尋求真理的人。
I don't want you to break your necks with those people
我不希望你與那些
who are just believing in discussion,
只相信爭論的人糾纏不清。
arguments and shabda jaal.
陷入討論、爭論與言語之網。
Today the Sahaja Yoga culture is so much manifesting
今日霎哈嘉瑜伽文化已如此顯著展現
that people, once they see you, they immediately know
以至於人們一旦見到你，便立刻知曉
there's something special
就能立刻感受到你的與眾不同，
and that they have something very unique
感受到你身上蘊藏著常人難得一見的獨特特質。
qualities among them which you seldom find with normal people.
這些特質在一般人身上很少見。
All these things, you should understand,
所有這些，你應該明白，
have come to you spontaneously from within,
都是從你內心自發而來的。
but you must preserve them and you should never feel shy of them.
但你必須保留它們，且永遠不應為此感到羞恥。
Should never be shy of your virtues.
永遠不應為你的美德感到羞恥。
And whatever people may try
無論人們如何試圖
to tell you that "You better do this and better do that"
告訴你「你最好這樣做、最好那樣做」
if it is wrong you should never do it.
如果那是錯的，你就不該去做。
Because, now, you are very powerful
因為，現在的你擁有強大的力量
Should just say, "I don't want to do it."
應該直接說：「我不想這麼做。」
and that you have to lead the people
而且你必須引領眾人
and people don't have to lead you.
而不是被他人引領。
Fashions don't have to lead you,
時尚不必引領你，
but you have to create fashions.
但你必須創造潮流。
You have to create a path for them.
你必須為他們開創一條道路。
It's not that you have to
並非你必須
trod on the path that they have made.
踏上他們鋪好的路。
Try to understand
試著去理解
that your own personality
你自身的個性
is of a level where you can see so many subtle things
你的境界已達到能洞察無數細微之處
and you are so powerful, that others don't see,
而你的力量如此強大，他人卻未能察覺
then you have to automatically take up their leadership.
那麼你必須自然而然地承擔起領導他們的責任
Don't get ideas from them
切勿從他們那裡汲取想法
and don't get frightened
而且不要感到害怕
when they try to tell you something
當他們試圖告訴你一些事情時
against yourself or against Sahaja Yoga.
無論是針對你個人還是針對霎哈嘉瑜伽
Be sure. Be confident. That is how it is going to work out.
要堅定。要有信心。事情就是這樣發展的。
Now, I'm just a woman and a housewife,
如今，我只是一位女性、一位家庭主婦，
but I was so sure about Sahaja Yoga
但我對霎哈嘉瑜伽深信不疑
that it worked out.
以至於它真的奏效了。
I didn't have to,
我原本不必如此，
sort of, think whether I should do it or not.
我幾乎不需要思考是否該這麼做，
I just started it.
我就直接開始了。
Though in the family it was not so much respected,
雖然在我的家庭中，它並沒有得到足夠的尊重和認可，
not so much agreed to, doesn't matter.
但這並不重要。
I started the whole thing on My own,
這整件事是我獨自開始的，
worked it out on My own,
也是我獨自完成的，
because I had complete confidence in the truth,
因為我對真理充滿了信心，
that if I am standing on the truth it will help Me
只要我站在真理這一邊，它就會幫助我
and it will help all those who will come to Me.
也會幫助所有那些將來到我面前的人。
It has happened.
這已經發生了。
So for you, it should not be difficult at all.
所以對你來說，這根本不應該有任何困難。
All of you should, first of all,
你們所有人都應該，首先，
see that you are not a conditioned person
明白你不是一個受制約的人
and you do not have an ego
而且不該有自我。
and then you should go ahead with it
那麼你就應該繼續前進
and you'll be amazed how things will work out.
你會驚訝於事情將如何順利發展。
Today's puja is very short puja.
今天的普迦儀式非常簡短。
That's why I gave you a long lecture.
所以我才講了這麼長的課。
There are so many things which I cannot,
有許多事情我無法，
at this time, which is short, tell you
在這麼短的時間內告訴你們。
but if you sit down, you can easily make
但如果你坐下來，你就能輕鬆地列出
one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight yourself.
一、二、三、四、五、六、七、八項。
So, now put your mind to it
所以，現在請專心致志
in a way that you are the organizer.
以一種你是組織者的方式。
Then what should you do? What can you do?
那麼你該怎麼做？你能做什麼？
What are you going to achieve?
你打算達成什麼目標？
Please try and it will work out.
請試試看，事情會解決的。
All of you can do it.
你們所有人都能做到。
I think best is to make a diary for yourself
我認為最好的方式是為自己製作一本日記
and write it down in that: what you have done,
並在其中記錄下來：你做了什麼、
how many people you have given realization,
你給予了多少人自覺、
how many got cured, what do you think about them.
多少人得到了治癒，你對他們有什麼想法。
But now, if there's no diary,
但現在，如果沒有日記，
Sahaja yogis can say among,
霎哈嘉瑜伽士們可以互相說，
"Mother, we have no diary, so we'll start it tomorrow." No,
「母親，我們沒有日記，所以我們明天再開始。」不，
you start it today.
你們今天就開始。
Only trouble with Sahaja yogis
霎哈嘉瑜珈士唯一的問題
is that they take things little lightly.
是他們對事情有點輕率。
Of course, that is their character.
當然，那是他們的性格。
But not Sahaja Yoga.
但霎哈嘉瑜珈並非如此。
Other things you can take lightly.
其他事情你可以輕鬆看待。
If somebody shouts at you,
如果有人對你大吼大叫，
somebody gets angry with you,
有人對你生氣，
somebody even slaps you, take it lightly.
甚至有人賞你耳光，都請輕鬆以對。
Doesn't matter, makes no difference to you,
沒關係，對你來說沒什麼差別，
because you are the spirit.
因為你就是那靈性。
Nothing can destroy the spirit.
沒有任何事物能摧毀靈。
Nainam Chidanti Shastrani.
Nainam Chidanti Shastrani。
But when it comes to Sahaja Yoga,
但當談到霎哈嘉瑜伽時，
your attitude should be different.
你的態度應該有所不同。
If you are relaxing on one side,
一方面，你放鬆身心；
another side you have to be dynamic
另一邊你必須保持動態
and that side is where you have to put forward
而那一邊正是你必須提出
the theories of Sahaja Yoga,
霎哈嘉瑜伽的理論，
when you have to talk to people,
當你需要與人們交談時，
you have to organize a press conference
你必須組織一場新聞發布會
or whatever sort of thing you want to do.
無論你想做什麼樣的事情。
At whatever level you want to work it out,
無論你想在哪個層次上解決它，
please make a proper plan about it
請為此制定一個適當的計劃
and just do it.
然後就去做吧。
It will all work out. I'm sure it will work out.
一切都會好起來的。我相信一切都會好轉的。
With all these ideas that I have,
儘管我腦中有這麼多想法，
you have many more
你們一定還有更多，
and I hope by next year,
而我期盼到了明年，
we'll see manifestation of those.
我們將會看到那些想法的實現。
I hope many people will write books
我希望有許多人會寫書
like U.C. Rai has written.
就像 U.C. Rai 所寫的那樣。
I'm sure books can be written by every doctor.
我相信每位醫生都能夠寫書。
Doctor U.C. Rai has worked single-handed.
U.C. Rai 醫生獨自一人完成了所有工作。
Everything he has done single-handed.
他所做的一切都是獨自完成的。
So beautifully he has worked it out.
他將這一切安排得如此完美。
So, everybody can publish a book with their experiences,
因此，每個人都可以出版一本關於自己經歷的書。
with their understanding of Sahaja Yoga,
憑藉他們對霎哈嘉瑜伽的理解，
which will help Sahaja yogis also.
這也將有助於霎哈嘉瑜伽士。
But it should be honest, very honest book.
但這必須是一本誠實、非常誠實的書。
I'm sure such a book will be very much appreciated
我確信這樣的書將會受到極大的讚賞。
in Sahaja Yoga and we would like to publish such books also.
在霎哈嘉瑜伽中，我們也希望能出版這類書籍。
All those who have such ideas
所有有這些想法的人
should make an effort to create some new books,
都應該努力創作一些新書、
some new ideas, some new creation.
一些新想法、一些新創作。
Is very important
這非常重要
because in these modern times
因為在現代社會
people want to do something new,
人們渴望嘗試新事物，
something novel.
追求新奇。
Under these circumstances,
在這樣的情況下，
I'm sure you all will work out.
我相信你們都能成功。
So, all the time we have to think about Sahaja Yoga
所以，我們必須時刻想著霎哈嘉瑜伽
and jot it down whatever ideas are coming into your mind
並將腦海中浮現的任何想法記錄下來
and then these can be properly put together,
然後這些就能妥善地組合起來，
making a beautiful book of Sahaja Yoga.
成為一本美麗的霎哈嘉瑜伽書籍。
Ladies also have lots of chances of doing
女士們也有許多機會為霎哈嘉瑜伽
so many things for Sahaja Yoga.
做很多事情。
This is a very opportune time.
這是一個非常恰當的時機。
I think Satya Yuga is starting from tomorrow. No doubt.
我認為善世（Satya Yuga）從明天開始（掌聲）。
And what will be the symptom
它的徵兆是什麼呢？
that now the satya will be victorious, vijaya.
那就是真理（Satya）將取得勝利，勝利（Vijaya）。
Whatever people may try,
無論人們如何嘗試，
ultimately satya will be vijaya.
最終真理必將勝利。
Satyame vijayate.
真理必勝（Satyameva Vijayate）。
That's going to happen and you are responsible.
這終將發生，而你有責任促成。
For this I congratulate you again and again.
為此，我再次恭喜你。
And I hope you will have the commitment to do that.
並且我希望你將有承諾去做到。
May God bless you all.
願上帝保佑你們所有人。